ALAA ABDELBAKI

Cloud computing student

**** 06 68 52 56 99

alaa.abdelbaki@outlook.com

Avignon, France

github.com/AlaaAbdelbaki

in /in/AlaaAbdelbaki

SUMMARY

Dedicated mobile software engineer with 2 years of experience in developing cross-platform applications with the Flutter framework. Proficient in multiple programming languages and technologies, including Dart, Java, Kotlin, Swift, and more. Strong ability to work on both front-end and back-end development, with a track record of successfully launching apps on Google Play Store and Apple App Store.

SKILLS

Languages: Dart, Java, Javascript, C#.

Technologies: Flutter, Git, Android, iOS, Jenkins, NestJS,

ExrpessJS, NextJS.

EXPERIENCE -

07/2023 - Present

Flutter developer

EButler

- Added new features to an existing Flutter application.
- · Worked on improving the real-time chatting feature using GetStream's Stream Chat library.
- · Maintained legacy code.
- · Upgraded the project to newer SDK versions, while performing the required code changes.
- · Pushed updates through Google Play.
- · Developed a redesigned version for mobile and web platforms while referencing a Figma design.
- Implemented new features and perform updates on a NestJS backend.
 Flutter / Riverpod / NestJs / Firebase / Firebase Cloud Messaging / GetStream / Google Play / App Store / WhatsApp Business API /

01/2022 - 06/2023

Software Engineer

Swiss Premium Negoce

- Defined the project's use cases and requirements.
- Decided which technologies to use based on the technical requirements.
- · Created the database design.
- · Developed the mobile application's UI based on an Adobe XD design.
- Added new features and updating existing ones.
- · Developed backend features.
- · Write backend documentation, following the OpenAPI standards.
- Implemented Google Cloud APIs in the mobile application (Google Maps / Google Directions)
- Integrated Stripe as a payment Gateway.
- Submitted and releasing the application on the Google Play Store and the Apple App Store.
 Flutter / Provider / Firebase / Firebase Cloud Messaging / Google Maps API / Google Directions API / ExpressJS / Stripe /

EDUCATION

09/2018 - 06/2022

Engineering degree in computer science

Private Higher School of Engineering and Technology (ESPRIT)

- Specialized in mobile applications development.
- Worked on various projects in different fields, including mobile development, web development, artificial intelligence, computer vision, and DevOps.

PROJECTS -

Flutter / ExpressJS

Elisys

A warehouse management mobile application, that helps technicians manage their products by simply scanning a QR code.

Flutter

Doroos

An online learning application, where users can choose from a wide variety of subjects and teachers, and chat with them in real time.

LANGUAGES

- English Fluent
- · French B2
- · Arabic Native